Julian F. Smith

Ingleside, Texas 78362

Phone: (361) 246-0493 | Email: smith.julian.f@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://juliansmith.dev | GitHub: https://github.com/Gamesmith9000

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/julian-f-smith

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a desire to help others with technology. Interested in the interaction of analytical and artistic thinking. Detail-oriented, with a history of attention to detail that eludes others. Excel at problem solving, research, and possess a strong skill base acquired through completion of a full stack web development program.

Technical Skills

• Database: PostgreSQL

• Deployment: Heroku, Netlify

- Frameworks & Libraries: Bootstrap, JQuery, Ruby on Rails
- Languages: C#, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Ruby, Sass
- Version Control: Bitbucket, Git, GitHub, SourceTree
- Other Tools: Amazon AWS (S3), Google Firebase (Realtime Database), Google Maps API, Slack, Skype, Stripe, Trello, Unity engine, Zoom

Projects

Each of the following web apps utilize PostgreSQL databases, the Ruby on Rails framework, and they are deployed using Heroku. These projects were created as part of the University of Texas Online Coding Bootcamp.

Nomster | GitHub: https://github.com/Gamesmith9000/Splurty/ | Live Site: https://nomster-julian-smith.herokuapp.com/

A Yelp-clone where users can create and edit, view, comment on, and rate place pages. Implements user validation and integrates Google Maps API.

Flixter | GitHub: https://github.com/Gamesmith9000/Flixter/ | Live Site: https://flixter-julian-smith.herokuapp.com/

Two-sided video lesson marketplace. Includes separate experiences for users and instructors, the capacity for credit card transactions, and uploading of user-generated video.

Grammable | GitHub: https://github.com/Gamesmith9000/Grammable/ | Live Site: https://github.com/Gamesmith9000/Grammable/ | Live Site: https://grammable-julian-smith.herokuapp.com/

This app is similar to Instagram and was created using test-driven development. Includes user validation and image uploading.

 $\textbf{Bro Chess} \mid \textbf{GitHub:} \underline{\text{https://github.com/BroCode2020/bro-chess/}} \mid \textbf{Live Site:} \underline{\text{https://bro-chess.herokuapp.com/}}$

A chess game team project using the agile methodology. Extensive use of version control, code review, and test-driven development. It also includes drag-and-drop functionality, SVG graphics, and Google Firebase integration for real-time updates.

Experience

Freelance Web Developer (Remote) Self-Employed

2020 to Present Ingleside, TX

- Implemented a simple framework to be utilized by client for content creation and management.
- Utilized Ruby on Rails, Sass, and JavaScript to create the app. Deployed on Heroku.

Front Desk Supervisor Fairfield by Marriott

2019-present Rockport, TX

- Coordinated with general manager and implemented new standard operating procedures, including updating of shift checklists.
- Wrote two new utility scripts for the FOSSE Property Management System (which is run on SecureCRT,

which allows scripting), to save time for employees.

- Created numerous spreadsheets for Inventory, Maintenance, Front Desk, and Management.
- Transferred hotel documents to cloud-based storage for uniform access across all devices.
- Trained new employees in hotel procedures and FOSSE Property Management System.

Optometric Technician Rockport Eye Associates

2017-2019 Rockport, TX

- Performed troubleshooting processes on multiple machines and computers and ensured that all systems interfaced properly.
- Verified and transcribed electronic health records.
- Operated medical diagnostic machines. Printed, scanned, and/or uploaded test data.

Front Desk Agent Microtel Inn & Suites

2017-2019

Aransas Pass, TX

- Assisted with getting hotel back open after Hurricane Harvey. Performed any and all tasks necessary to reopening the hotel, including emptying rooms, moving inventory large and small, cleaning, and coordinating with various workers and contractors.
- Before opening to the public, worked Front Desk and helped with simple maintenance while hosting workers tasked with restoring power lines for the area.
- Mastered Synxis Property Management System. Became adept at identifying specifics of the interface that gave new users trouble.
- Continued to assist at property while maintaining a full-time job.
- Accepted job opportunity from hotel ownership to return to the soon to reopen Fairfield by Marriott Rockport, Texas in a supervisor position.

Front Desk Agent Fairfield Inn & Suites (now Fairfield by Marriott)

2016-2017

Rockport, TX

- Combined and modified two separate sources to create standard shift checklists
- Produced tailor-made, eco-friendly version of the contingency reports. Created a utility script for the FOSSE Property Management System to automate printing reports.
- Relocated to another property after current hotel was severely disabled by Hurricane Harvey. Joined the team at the Microtel Inn & Suites Aransas Pass, Texas, another property under the same ownership, that required help with reopening and additional staff.

Night Auditor Hampton Inn & Suites

2016-2017

Rockport, TX

- Transmitted electronic credit payment data, utilizing a separate verification service.
- Allocated housekeeping room assignments. Created custom spreadsheets for room types and counts.
 Built custom printout that assured fair and balanced distribution.
- Accepted job invitation from employers to work at their new Fairfield Inn & Suites in Rockport, Texas.

Education

Coding Bootcamp Certificate: The University of Texas Austin, Texas (Remote)

97 hours of completed coursework towards Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology: Texas A&M University College Station, TX